Bro, what's the big hurry?
あにき…もう少しゆっくり歩いてくれよ
Dororo.
どろろ。
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
どうした
な…なんでもないよ
Let's go.
行くぞ
Out of our way!
どけどけーっ！
Those guys are probably Asakura scouts.
いまのやつら、たぶん朝倉の斥候だ。
They came from the direction
of Daigo's land.
それが醍醐領のほうから走ってきた！
-I see.
-Wait, bro!
そうか…
待ってくれあにき！
I have a really bad feeling about this.
おいら…なんだか嫌な予感がするよ
No matter.
構わない。
My body is in Daigo's land.
醍醐に身体がある
Betrayed this world
And it simmers within
Rupturing my innards
Swelling a reddish black
Until the sun burnt skin ruptures
There is a light
in the depths of the seething darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
There is a light
in the depths of the darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
#21 The story of breaking the cycle of suffering
Reporting, sir!
申し上げます！
Two new villages in the territory
have been affected by the epidemic.
新たに領内2つの村で、流行り病いが出た模様でございます
We have no choice.
やむを得まい。
Burn down the villages.
Make sure it doesn't spread.
村ごと焼き払え。近隣まで広がらぬようにいたせ
Reporting, sir!
申し上げます！
The Asakura clan is gathering up
their army.
朝倉軍、着々と兵が集まりつつあるとのこと！
Around 2,000 soldiers.
その数、およそ2千！
-Are they about to advance?
-No sir, not yet.
動きそうか
いえ…まだその気配は見られませぬ
How about our army and its provisions?
我が軍の兵と兵糧はどうなっている
We're rounding up men from allies
and unaffected villages.
同盟国、および災難に見舞われていない村からの徴用確保を
進めておりますが…
But it is not enough.
今だ充分とは…
Hurry it up!
遅い！急がせろ！
The days of prosperity
for this land are over.
この国の安寧のときは…終わりまする
No!
嫌だ！
Forgive us...
許せ…
All men who can walk
will be drafted as soldiers.
動ける男は残れ！兵として徴用する！
Get going!
モタモタするな！
Couldn't you pardon just a couple of men?
せめて2、3人だけ村に残すわけにはいかねぇですか。
The women and children
can't handle all the work.
女子供だけじゃぁ、力仕事が…
This land is in danger.
What is more important!
国の一大事に、気にかけている場合か！
I never imagined you'd come this far
to round up horses.
こんな辺鄙なところまで馬を取りにおいでなさるとは…
It must be quite a situation.
よほどのことなんで？
What a fine horse. We'll take it.
おぉ…これは見事な馬だ！貰うぞ！
Midoro is my finest horse.
She's our breadwinner.
このミドロは、うちの稼ぎ頭でして
Please return her to us unharmed.
どうか怪我をさせずに戻してくださいまし
This isn't the time for that.
We are fighting for our land.
勝手なことを言うな！我らは国のために戦うのだぞ！
Come on now.
さぁ来い…
You will obey me!
言うことを聞け！
You little...
こいつ…！
Oh dear...
な…なんてことを…
You, lend a hand!
お前も手を貸せぃ！
Yes sir.
はい…！
They're headed this way.
着々とこちらへと向かっております
You're positive it's Hyakkimaru?
間違いなく百鬼丸だろうな
Yes, I am quite sure.
That child is also with him.
確かにございます。いつも連れている子供もおりました。
He will reach this territory
within a few days.
数日のうちに領内へ入るかと
So he has come.
やはり来るか…
Asakura will be on the move by then.
What shall we do?
その頃には朝倉も動くはず。いかがいたしましょう
I shall go and dispose of Hyakkimaru.
ならば私が百鬼丸を討ちます
A small troop would be no match for him.
兵をいくらか集めたとて、奴にはかないませぬ。
Yet, we cannot afford to send
a whole army just now.
とはいえ今は、全軍を向かわせるわけにもいきますまい
I will need no other
as long as I have Mutsu and Hyogo.
陸奥と兵庫がいれば、他に兵は要りません。
Father, if we don't dispose
of Hyakkimaru now,
父上。ここで百鬼丸を討てぬならば、
we will never be able to
govern this land in peace.
この先醍醐を治めていくことなど到底できませぬ！
Fine. Go, my son.
よかろう。行ってまいれ
Are you sure, my lord?
よろしいので？
You saw his eyes.
あの目を見たであろう。
Nobody can stop him.
止められはせぬ。
I have a job for you.
…お前にやってもらうことがある
Hey bro?
なぁ。あにき…
What?
なんだ
When we reach Daigo, what if, well...
醍醐に行ってさ。もしも…もしもまた、
What will you do
if your papa and mama come?
あにきのお父ちゃんやおっかちゃんが来たら…どうするんだ？
If they get in my way, I will kill.
邪魔するなら…斬る
But if you do that,
でも、そんなことしたらこの先一生…
you'll never ever be able
to be by their side again.
何があっても、そばにいられなくなっちまうんだぞ！？
I'll have you.
どろろがいる
What are you doing?
何をしている。
Young Master awaits.
若がお待ちだ
Will many die again?
また…たくさん死ぬのか。
Like how we almost did?
あのときの俺らのような人たちが
I hate wars.
戦は嫌だ
Yes. We must defeat Hyakkimaru
and bring an end to all this.
あぁ。何としても百鬼丸を倒し、終わらせなければならぬ
I know.
わかっている…
I will not let my people
suffer any longer.
これ以上…この国の民を苦しませるわけにはいかぬ。
Let us go exorcise the evil!
災いを払いに行くぞ！
I see.
そうでしたか…
So Tahomaru has gone for Hyakkimaru.
多宝丸は、百鬼丸の元へ
Yes, my lady.
はい
Hyakkimaru is like a baby
who has come crying to take his toy back.
今の百鬼丸は…
取り上げられた玩具を泣いて取り戻しに来る幼子のようなもの。
No words can reach him now.
きっと…誰の言葉も届かないでしょう
And it is the same for Tahomaru.
そしてそれは…
He is turning himself into an incarnation
of Asura for the sake of Daigo.
醍醐のため、修羅の化身となろうとする多宝丸も同じ
The wife of a lord,
or the mother of children.
領主の妻か、子を持つ母か。
Had I have been just one and not both,
I wouldn't have cursed my helplessness.
どちらか一方であったなら、己の無力さを呪うこともなかったでしょう
My lady...
御方様…
Hyakkimaru...
百鬼丸…
Tahomaru...
多宝丸
Hey, you there.
あ…おい、ちょっと待ちな
Are you two from Daigo?
あんたら、醍醐の人かい
No, why?
違うけど
Then you better turn back.
だったら悪いことは言わねぇ。すぐに引き返せ。
There's gonna be a huge war here
with Asakura.
もうすぐ朝倉との大いくさが始まるぞ
I came all this way because
they said I'd make a fortune here.
ったく醍醐に行きゃ儲けられるって言うから、
この田舎くんだりまで来たのによぉ…
But hey, nothing's more precious
than your life.
あんたらも、命あっての物種だぜ
Hey!
あぁ…おい！
Bro!
あにき！
Out of my way.
邪魔…するな
What the heck, bro?
何やってんだよ！
You heard him, there's going to be a war.
あにき、聞いたろ！？やっぱり戦が起こるんだ。
I know how you feel,
but now isn't the time.
気持ちはわかるけど、今はやめよう！
No. I'm getting my body back.
ダメだ。身体を取り戻す
But you heard the old guy.
今はおっちゃんの言うとおりだ！
Nothing's more precious
than your life, right?
死んじまったらどうにもなんないんだってば！
I'm getting it back.
取り戻す
Fine. But I'm not going with you.
うっ！だったらおいら、ついて行ってやんねーぞ！
Why? They're the ones that took it.
なぜだ。奪ったのは奴らだ！
I just...
おいらはただ…
I don't want you to become someone else.
あにきがあにきでなくなっちまうのが嫌なんだ。
I'm scared!
怖いんだよ！
Why would I not be me?
なぜ俺じゃなくなる！
To touch with my hands.
To see with my eyes.
俺の手で触る
俺の目で見る！
I want to feel.
俺も感じる…
Just like you.
どろろと同じに
Dang it.
ちくしょう…
What am I supposed to do?
おいら…どうしたらいいんだよ…
Gosh dang it...
ちくしょう…ちくしょう…
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
Yes, I just seem to be a bit tense.
えぇ。どうやら少し気が張っているようで
I've never seen you like that.
そうか…珍しいな
Hyogo...
兵庫は…
Is just like always.
相変わらずか
He sure is.
困ったものです
We've been together for a long time now.
思えばずいぶんと共にいるな
How long has it been
since Lord Daigo saved Hyogo and me?
景光様に助けられ、もう何年になりますか
You have done well to survive.
Don't worry now.
よくぞ生き抜いた。もう大丈夫だ
So you sharpened a corpse's bone.
骸の骨を削ったか。
Rest easy, I am not your enemy.
案ずるな。我らは敵ではない
Tahomaru.
多宝丸。
This is Mutsu and Hyogo.
ここにおるは陸奥と兵庫だ。
They will stay here from today on.
今日よりこの屋敷にとどめ置く。
They will study and train with you.
これからは共に学問や剣術に励め
Mutsu, Hyogo.
陸奥。兵庫。
I will strive for peace
together with my father.
私は父上とともに、太平の世を目指す。
So no more people die senseless deaths
or go through such hardships as you have.
こうして死にゆく者も、お前たちのように辛い思いをする者もいない世だ
And for that, I will make Daigo
the strongest domain in the land.
そのために…醍醐を天下一の強国にするぞ
Our aspirations are as one
with yours and Lord Daigo's.
我らが望みは、景光様と若の宿願に同じ。
I have humbly become your right hand.
私は及ばずながら、若の右腕となり、
Hyogo has become your left.
We will protect you with all that we have.
兵庫は左腕として宿願成就のその時まで
Until the day
your ambitions are fulfilled.
全身全霊でお守りいたします
The day is near.
成就の時は…すぐそこだ
Yes, sir.
はい
I will not let this domain fall.
この国を…終わらせはせぬ
Onward, march!
いざ！出陣！
Advance! Daigo is nothing to be afraid of!
進めぇー！醍醐など恐るるに足らずー！
Bro, it's them again.
あにき、またあいつらが
Tahomaru.
多宝丸…
Stand back.
離れていろ！
No, you can't! He's your little brother.
ダメだあにき！あいつはあにきの弟だぞ！
No!
違う！
He called me a demon.
あれは…俺を鬼神と呼んだ…
His rage is unlike before.
Be careful, sir.
前とは比べ物にならぬ殺気。ご用心を
Hyakkimaru.
You will not harm this land any further.
百鬼丸…これ以上醍醐を穢させはせん。
I, Tahomaru, will slay you here.
この多宝丸が、ここで貴様を討つ！
Mutsu!
陸奥！
Hyogo!
兵庫！
His right arm...!
右腕が！
You demon, bane of our land.
醍醐に仇なす鬼神め…
I will kill you
if it's the last thing I do!
この命を懸けて、貴様を葬ってくれる！
Bro!
あにき！
Bro...
ぁあにき…！
You're coming with us.
お前はこっちだ
Let go!
離せ！うっ！
Bro, bro...!
あにき！あにきぃーっ！
Why are you here?
なぜ貴様が…
Lord Daigo ordered me
to look after you discreetly.
景光様の命により、密かにお守りしておりました
Tahomaru will succeed me.
多宝丸は醍醐の世継ぎ。
Make sure he returns to this castle alive.
必ず生きてこの城に戻らせよ
Please, you must retreat.
ここは退いてくださいませ
Out of my way!
どけ！
I must defeat Hyakkimaru
or this land will be done for.
百鬼丸を倒さねば、この国は滅ぶ！
-They are the lord's orders.
-I don't care.
殿の命にございます！
聞かぬ！
Forgive me.
御免…！
Hyakki... maru...
百鬼…丸…
Young Master!
若！
Carry him.
お運びしろ
Hey, stop it. Let go!
おい！やめろよ…離せよ！
I said let go of me, you jerk!
おい！離せってんだバカヤロ！
Why the child?
その子供は！
Hyakkimaru is still alive.
百鬼丸にとどめを刺せておらぬ。
We need him, just in case.
万が一のためだ
It is cowardly to use the helpless!
力なき者を利用するは卑劣！
I care not for your sentiments.
貴様らの理屈などどうでもよい！
Even if it breaks you,
even if it turns you into the devil...
己の身が滅びようが、その魂を捻じ曲げようが、
It's your job to protect Young Master!
若をお守りするのがお役目であろう！
Shame on you for being saved by him!
なぜ貴様らが若に助けられている！
Let's go.
行くぞ
Bro!
あにき！
Bro...!
あ…あにきぃーっ！
Do... roro...
あ…ど…ろろ…
Born into this world
There is no salvation
The distorted shape of the heart
Yet it beats courageously
There is no turning back
Even from the path of evil
Witnessing the withering seasons
We search for the truth
In our ugliness
We don't even recognize the pain
As we peel back the skin
We are forever tormented by our stupidity
But if the dawn never comes
Through the painful night
You who distrusts nothing
You will be able to love
this accursed world
Now that we carry the world
on our shoulders
It's time to take it back
"Midoro"